<events>
	<event><event-id value="bc1d4dfc7f00000100258097141c1960"/><start-time value="July 29, 2011"/><title value="Four Corners Summer Festival: Dance"></title><short-description value="Four Corners Summer Festival Presents: Dance"/><full-description><p><strong>Description:</strong> Millersville University's Four Corners Summer Festival celebrates the "four corners" of the arts: dance, music, art and theater.</p>
<p>Dancers Edge Performing the &#8220;Swan Pond&#160;Ballet&#8221; Choreographed for Millersville 250 Anniversary.</p>
<p><strong>Ticket Information:</strong> The festival is FREE and open to the public.</p>
<p>Sponsored by: Millersville University, Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, Arts and Education Partnership, 250 Millersville Committee and South Central PARTners.</p></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=bc1d4dfc7f00000100258097141c1960"/></event><event><event-id value="6b246fe07f00000100258097a3ec8278"/><start-time value="September 19, 2011"/><title value="Immigration Experience Symposium Keynote Address: Sonia Nazario, author"></title><short-description value="One Book, One Campus presents a keynote address by author Sonia Nazario"/><full-description><meta content="text/html; charset=utf-8"/>
<meta content="Word.Document" name="ProgId"/>
<meta content="Microsoft Word 11" name="Generator"/>
<meta content="Microsoft Word 11" name="Originator"/>
<link href="file:///C:%5CDOCUME%7E1%5Cduncan14%5CLOCALS%7E1%5CTemp%5Cmsohtml1%5C06%5Cclip_filelist.xml" rel="File-List"/><p><strong>Description:</strong> A keynote address by Sonia Nazario, author of <em>Enrique's Journey</em>, will take place following the Understanding the Immigrant Experience Symposium: The Changing Face of Our County and Country, on September 19 at 7 p.m. The keynote address will take place in Pucillo Gymnasium.</p>
<p>This event is held in conjunction with the University's One Book, One Campus program, which is hosting multiple programs throughout the academic year focused around this year's selection of&#160;<em>Enrique's Journey</em> to enrich students.</p>
<p><strong>Ticket Information:</strong> This event is FREE and open to the public.</p></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=6b246fe07f00000100258097a3ec8278"/></event><event><event-id value="8ee864617f000001002580970f74fe51"/><start-time value="September 24, 2011"/><title value="Faculty Recital: &quot;Fingers con Fuoco: Fast, Furious, and with Feeling&quot;"></title><short-description value="Millersville University's Department of Music presents a faculty recital."/><full-description><p><strong>Description:</strong> "Fingers con Fuoco: Fast, Furious, and with Feeling," a Faculty Recital. Join clarinetist Dr. Christy Banks and pianist Dr. Anita Renfroe, along with an appearance by the Millersville University Clarinet Ensemble. Fingers will fly! Works by Bernstein, Arnold, Kovacs, Kalliwoda, Lowenstern and Schickele.<br/>
<br/>
<strong>Ticket Information:</strong> General Admission-$10, Students w/ ID-Free. Tickets may be purchased online, at <a href="www.MUTicketsOnline.com">www.MUTicketsOnline.com</a>, in the Student Memorial Center Ticket Office (Room 103), by calling the Ticket Office, at 717-872-3811 or at Millersville University Lancaster, 42 N. Prince St., Lancaster, Monday through Friday, 8 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.</p>
<p>Photo of Dr. Banks courtesy of: russell g. frost of frostimaging.com</p></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=8ee864617f000001002580970f74fe51"/></event><event><event-id value="5d65c8297f000001002580974a82b29d"/><start-time value="October 6, 2011"/><title value="Carter G. Woodson Lecture: Charles Dutton - &quot;From Jail to Yale&quot;"></title><short-description value="Carter G. Woodson Lecture with Charles Dutton, Emmy Award-Winning Actor and Director"/><full-description><p><strong>Description:</strong> Charles Dutton, Emmy award-wining actor and director will present the Carter G. Woodson Lecture on October 6 at 7:30 p.m. His lecture, titled, "From Jail to Yale," will be held at Bright Side Baptist Church, 515 Hershey Ave., Lancaster.</p>
<p><strong>Biography:</strong> Best known for his starring role as "Roc" as well as Emmy-winning guest roles in "The Practice" and "Without a Trace," Dutton, a graduate of Yale, worked with acclaimed playwright, August Wilson. He appeared in Wilson's "Ma Rainey's Black Bottom" and "The Piano Lesson," both of which earned him Tony nominations. He also starred in Wilson's Pulitzer Prize winning play, "Joe Turner's Come and Gone." His directing credits include feature film, "Against the Ropes," miniseries, "The Corner" and television movie, "First Time Felon."</p>
<p><strong>Ticket Information:</strong> This event is FREE and open to the public.</p></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=5d65c8297f000001002580974a82b29d"/></event><event><event-id value="e5cc67ce7f000001002580978e1b80f4"/><start-time value="October 21, 2011"/><title value="University Theatre presents: Teibele and Her Demon"></title><short-description value="Playwrights Singer and Friedman create a dark world of mystery and superstition in this story of love, passion and deception."/><full-description><p><strong>Description</strong>: Millersville University Theatre presents, "Teibele and her Demon," a fable by Isaac Bashevis Singer and Eve Friedman, who create a dark world of mystery and superstition in this story of love, passion and deception.</p>
<p>In a Polish Jewish village in the late 19th century lives Teibele, a young attractive woman whose husband has deserted her and apparently disappeared. Teibele can't remarry until he's legally declared dead. Alchonon, a woe-begone, unemployed scholar, loves Teibele from afar, but she despises him. But Alchonon knows of Teibele's fascination for biblical demons and their powers, and devises an outrageous plan to woo and win her in the dark. His plan succeeds; disguised as a demon, he captures the heart of his Teibele, but can he ever win her love in the real world?</p>
<p>The production will run in Rafter's Theatre of Dutcher Hall on the following dates and times:</p>
<p><strong>October 21, 22, 27, 28 and 29 at 8 p.m.</strong></p>
<p><strong>October 23 (open captioned) and 30 at 2 p.m.</strong></p>
<p>Directed by Tony Elliot and produced by special arrangements with Samuel French, Inc. PG 13 - MATURE THEMES</p>
<p><strong>Ticket Information:</strong></p>
<p>$10.00 General Admission</p>
<p>$7.00 MU ID, Senior Citizens and Students</p>
<p>$5.00 MU ID super saver advance sales only at the Student Memorial Center (SMC)</p>
<p>It is suggested you purchase your tickets in advance because of the limited seating the Rafter's Theatre.Tickets can be purchased Monday through Friday, 8 a.m. - 4 p.m. at the Student Memorial Center (SMC) Ticket Office (Room 103) or by calling the Ticket Office at 717-872-3811 and online at <a href="www.MUTicketsOnline.com">www.MUTicketsOnline.com<br/>
</a></p></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=e5cc67ce7f000001002580978e1b80f4"/></event><event><event-id value="d71ee21b7f000001002580974de5a33f"/><start-time value="October 23, 2011"/><title value="University Theatre presents: Teibele and Her Demon"></title><short-description value="Playwrights Singer and Friedman create a dark world of mystery and superstition in this story of love, passion and deception."/><full-description><p><strong>Description</strong>: Millersville University Theatre presents, "Teibele and her Demon," a fable by Isaac Bashevis Singer and Eve Friedman, who create a dark world of mystery and superstition in this story of love, passion and deception.</p>
<p>In a Polish Jewish village in the late 19th century lives Teibele, a young attractive woman whose husband has deserted her and apparently disappeared. Teibele can't remarry until he's legally declared dead. Alchonon, a woe-begone, unemployed scholar, loves Teibele from afar, but she despises him. But Alchonon knows of Teibele's fascination for biblical demons and their powers, and devises an outrageous plan to woo and win her in the dark. His plan succeeds; disguised as a demon, he captures the heart of his Teibele, but can he ever win her love in the real world?</p>
<p>The production will run in Rafter's Theatre of Dutcher Hall on the following dates and times:</p>
<p><strong>October 21, 22, 27, 28 and 29 at 8 p.m.</strong></p>
<p><strong>October 23 (open captioned) and 30 at 2 p.m.</strong></p>
<p>Directed by Tony Elliot and produced by special arrangements with Samuel French, Inc. PG 13 - MATURE THEMES</p>
<p><strong>Ticket Information:</strong></p>
<p>$10.00 General Admission</p>
<p>$7.00 MU ID, Senior Citizens and Students</p>
<p>$5.00 MU ID super saver advance sales only at the Student Memorial Center (SMC)</p>
<p>It is suggested you purchase your tickets in advance because of the limited seating the Rafter's Theatre.Tickets can be purchased Monday through Friday, 8 a.m. - 4 p.m. at the Student Memorial Center (SMC) Ticket Office (Room 103) or by calling the Ticket Office at 717-872-3811 and online at <a href="www.MUTicketsOnline.com">www.MUTicketsOnline.com</a></p></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=d71ee21b7f000001002580974de5a33f"/></event><event><event-id value="4317051f7f00000100258097ef628a90"/><start-time value="October 29, 2011"/><title value="Day of African Events"></title><short-description value="Millersville University's Department of Music African Dance Symposium presents: A Day of African Events."/><full-description><p><strong>Description:</strong> On October 29, Millersville University's music department is presenting "A Day of African Drumming, Dance and Performance," featuring Baile's African Drum Works Ensemble.</p>
<p>The day includes a drumming workshop, a dance workshop and culminates with an energetic performance of traditional African music, dance, drama and folklore with drummers, dancers, singing, masquerades and lots of energy. All the events will be located within the Millersville University Lancaster location downtown.</p>
<p>The drumming workshop is from 10:30 a.m. - noon; the dance workshop is from 1 - 2:45 p.m. and the performance by Baile's African Drumworks Ensemble begins at 7 p.m.</p>
<p><strong>Ticket Information:</strong> For each workshop, the cost to attend is the following:</p>
<p>Drumming workshop - $20 at the door, $15 in advance, $10 students;</p>
<p>Dance workshop - $20 at the door, $15 in advance, $10 students;</p>
<p>Evening performance: $20 adults, $15 students</p>
<p>Tickets may be purchased online, at <a href="redir.aspx?C=ad6112656d6a40739773546d6cb37def&amp;URL=http%3a%2f%2fwww.MUTicketsOnline.com" target="_blank">www.MUTicketsOnline.com</a>, in the Student Memorial Center Ticket Office (Room 103), by calling the Ticket Office at 717-872-3811, or at Millersville University Lancaster, 42 N. Prince St., Lancaster. Ticket offices are open Monday - Friday, 8 a.m. - 4:30 p.m.</p></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=4317051f7f00000100258097ef628a90"/></event><event><event-id value="6238c3957f000001002580977a7d1e33"/><start-time value="October 29, 2011"/><title value="Homecoming Event: Millersville's Community Parade"></title><short-description value="Celebrate Millersville University's Homecoming weekend at the Millersville Community Parade"/><full-description><p><strong>Description</strong>: During Millersville University's Homecoming celebration, the Millersville Community Parade will be held on Saturday, October 29. This year's theme is Our American Heritage: Celebrating Millersville's 250th Anniversary.</p>
<p>Beginning at 9 a.m., this three-hour, prize-winning parade attracts more then 6,000 spectators along a two-mile route with 2,300 participants. Entries include 15 varied music groups (i.e., University and high school bands, drum and bugle corps, bagpipers, U.S. Armed Forces bands, a steel drum band, Philadelphia Mummers band), floats, impersonators, mascots, fire and emergency groups, twirlers, live animals, antique vehicles and more. The 2011 parade will be dedicated to a local U.S. Marine, Eric Torbert, killed in Afghanistan (2010). Also, the parade committee is working with the Toys for Tots Program to collect toys from parade spectators on parade day.</p>
<p>Parade Route: Herr Ave/Landis Ave/George St.</p>
<p><strong>Ticket Information</strong>: This event is free and open to the public.</p>
<br/></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=6238c3957f000001002580977a7d1e33"/></event><event><event-id value="43471dcd7f000001002580972dad2bef"/><start-time value="October 30, 2011"/><title value="Fall Percussion Extravaganza"></title><short-description value="Millersville University's Department of Music Percussion Symposium presents the Fall Percussion Extravaganza."/><full-description><p><strong>Description:</strong> Millersville University welcomes Brazilian solo marimba artist Gilmar Goulart in his first Pennsylvania appearance. Goulart will be joined by acclaimed Overdekte Brug PercussieTrio and the Millersville University Percussion Ensemble. A wide variety of percussion music will be presented in solo and ensemble form in this special event.</p>
<p><strong>Gilmar Goulart Biography:</strong> Goulart is head of the Percussion Department Studies at the Federal University of Santa Maria, Brazil. He finished his DMA in 2001 at the University of Colorado at Boulder, with Douglas Walter; studied with Ian Wright at the Royal Northern College of Music, Manchester, England; and Ney Rosauro in Santa Maria. At the RNCM he became the first marimbist to be awarded the Professional Performance Diploma with Distinction. He also presented the British premiere of David Maslanka;"Concerto for Marimba and Winds, with the RNCM Wind Orchestra. Goulart has recorded two CDs:"The World of Marimba, (1998), and "The Moods of Marimba (2006). He has presented many Brazilian premieres of important composers for percussion such as Christopher Deane, Eric Ewazen, James Ure, David Jones. He has also commissioned works for solo marimba from composers in Brazil, USA, and Europe. As a clinician, he has taught courses and seminar s in Brazil and Argentina and the U.S.</p>
<p><strong>Overdekte Brug Percussietrio Biography:</strong> Covering a multitude of percussion styles that bridge all extremes of emotion and musical possibility, Overdekte Brug Percussietrio creates a unique niche in the evolving world of percussion performance. Featuring the talents of Dr. Daniel Heslink, James Armstrong, and Steve Goss this Central Pennsylvania based ensemble shows no remorse when pushing the boundaries of musical expression and creativity. From the avant-garde to the traditional, from Cage to Corea, the excitement that Overdekte Brug Percussietrio brings to each performance is certainly memorable and unprecedented.</p>
<p><strong>Millersville University Percussion Ensemble Bio:</strong> Under the direction of James Armstrong, 20 members strong, the Percussion and Mallet Ensembles are comprised of the percussion majors and minors in the Millersville University music department. The members find percussion and mallet ensembles to serve as an important part of their training, and are dedicated to the furtherance of percussion ensemble music as one of America's most exciting art forms. The ensemble is support by MU's significant collection of fine percussion instruments and outstanding ensemble library. Both the Mallet and Percussion Ensembles have performed extensively on tours, at the East Coast Percussion Ensemble Festival, at Percussive Arts Society events and children's concerts. In existence for more than 30 years, these ensembles are credited with the premiers of many new works and arrangements for the medium.</p>
<p><strong>Ticket Information:</strong> Tickets are $10 general admission and FREE for students with ID. Tickets may be purchased online, at <a href="redir.aspx?C=ad6112656d6a40739773546d6cb37def&amp;URL=http%3a%2f%2fwww.MUTicketsOnline.com" target="_blank">www.MUTicketsOnline.com</a>, in the Student Memorial Center Ticket Office (Room 103), by calling the Ticket Office at 717-872-3811, or at Millersville University Lancaster, 42 N. Prince St., Lancaster. Ticket offices are open Monday - Friday, 8 a.m. - 4:30 p.m.</p></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=43471dcd7f000001002580972dad2bef"/></event><event><event-id value="5826bc367f0000010025809778d16e00"/><start-time value="November 3, 2011"/><title value="Cookin with Soul"></title><short-description value="&quot;Cookin with Soul&quot; A sample of a traditional soul food dinner accompanied by the sounds of smooth jazz"/><full-description><p><strong>Description:</strong> Enjoy fried chicken, macaroni and cheese, cornbread and many more traditional African American foods while listening to Millersville's own Jazz ensemble!</p>
<p><strong>Ticket Information:</strong> This event is FREE and open to the public.</p></full-description><path value="http://www.millersville.edu/calendar/eventdetails.php?id=5826bc367f0000010025809778d16e00"/></event>
</events>